Guide to the Miguel A. Gandert Photographs and Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- June 2005 Acquisition, 1983-2003; 4; 1.38; (15 boxes)
  - Photographs
    - Varrio San José: Scenes from an Urban Chicano Experience, This group of material consists of photographic prints, 16 inches by 20 inches, mounted in mats, 22 inches by 28 inches.
      - First Plaza, Downtown Albuquerque, New Mexico, 1983 (Box 88 (Oversize))
        Alternate title in brochure for the exhibition at the National Museum of American History, Smithsonian Institution, Washington, D.C.: Bathers.
      - Lawrence and Lyla, 1986 (Box 88 (Oversize))
    - Voces de la Tierra: Tierra Sagrada: The Sacred Land
      This group of photographs comes from an exhibition that documents traditional Hispano farming at Albuquerque Museum, Albuquerque, New Mexico, October 10, 1999-January 3, 2000.
      Arrangement follows original order of the exhibition. Organized under two headings by print size: 16 inches by 20 inches and 14 inches by 20 inches.
      - 16 inches by 20 inches, This subseries consists of photographic prints, 16 inches by 20 inches, in mats, 22 inches by 28 inches.
        - Adelmo Kaber Sanchez and His Son Edwin Sanchez, Planting Winter Wheat, San Luis, Colorado, 1997 (Box 89 (Oversize))
        - 97 year Romaldita Kaber, Cleaning Spinach, San Luis, Colorado, 1997 (Box 89 (Oversize))
        - Old Praxiades Ortega, San Luis, Colorado, 1995 (Box 89 (Oversize))
        - Estevan Arellano, Irrigating His Milpa, Embudo, New Mexico, 1998 (Box 89 (Oversize))
        - Adelmo Kaber, Prepares Land for Planting, San Luis, Colorado, 1997 (Box 89 (Oversize))
        - Mexican Migrants Harvest Peas, San Luis, Colorado, 1997 (Box 89 (Oversize))
        - Cattle Grazing on the San Luis Commons, San Luis, Colorado, 1995 (Box 90 (Oversize))
        - Iglesia de San Acacio, Old San Acacio, Colorado., 1997 (Box 90 (Oversize))
        - Los Mayordomos de San Isidro, Fiesta de San Isidro, San Luis, Colorado, 1997 (Box 90 (Oversize))
        - Entrega de San Isidro, Fiesta de San Isidro, Atrisco, Albuqurque, New Mexico, 1997 (Box 90 (Oversize))
        - Malinche and Matachines, Fiesta de San Isidro, Atrisco, Albuquerque, New Mexico, 1997 (Box 90 (Oversize))
        - Shovels for Adobes, La Cueva, New Mexico, 1992 (Box 90 (Oversize))
          Alternate title: Shovels.
        - Cutting Hay, Rodarte, New Mexico, 1985 (Box 91 (Oversize))
        - Elias Hurtado, Cutting Alfalfa, Agua Negra, New Mexico, 1999 (Box 91 (Oversize))
        - Logging Truck, Jarosa Gate Taylor Ranch, San Luis Colorado, 1996 (Box 91 (Oversize))
        - Earth First Protestor, San Francisco Gate Taylor Ranch, San Luis, Colorado, 1996 (Box 91 (Oversize))
        - Protestors Parade, Fiesta de Santa Anna y Santiago, San Luis, Colorado, 1996 (Box 91 (Oversize))
        - Blockade, Jarosa Gate Taylor Ranch, San Luis, Colorado, 1996 (Box 91 (Oversize))
        - Pilgrim With Cross, Tomé, New Mexico, 1991; 2 (Box 92 (Oversize))
        - Morada, Lower Las Colonias, New Mexico, 1989 (Box 92 (Oversize))
        - Juan Roybal, Lower Las Colonias, New Mexico, 1989 (Box 92 (Oversize))
        - Los Chileros, La Puebla, New Mexico, 1992 (Box 92 (Oversize))
        - Matanza, Los Trujillos, New Mexico, 1989 (Box 92 (Oversize))
        - Doña Agueda Martinez, La Madura, New Mexico, 1992 (Box 93 (Oversize))
        - Richard Mares and Seferino Lucero, South Valley, Albuquerque, New Mexico, 1983 (Box 93 (Oversize))
        - Guadalupe Rael, Good Friday, El Cerro, Tomé, New Mexico, 1989 (Box 93 (Oversize))
        - Respect, Tomé, New Mexico, 1993 (Box 93 (Oversize))
          Alternate title and date in Nuevo México Profundo: Cumbre de la Cruz, Tomé, 1996.
        - Adelmo Kaber and Veronica Sanchez, Separating Seed from Chaff, San Luis, Colorado, 1997 (Box 93 (Oversize))
        - Adelmo Kaber, Potato Cellar, San Luis, Colorado, 1995 (Box 93 (Oversize))
        - Acequia Madre Rodarte, New Mexico, 1999 (Box 93 (Oversize))
        - Mexican Migrant Child, San Luis, Colorado, 1997 (Box 93 (Oversize))
        - Acequia Canoe, Trampas, New Mexico, 1999 (Box 94 (Oversize))
        - Pilgrim With Cross, Good Friday, El Cerro, 1989 (Box 94 (Oversize))
        - Trompetas y Clarines, Tomé, New Mexico, 1992 (Box 94 (Oversize))
        - Amador Flores, Tierra Amarilla, 1988 (Box 94 (Oversize))
        - Frederico, Tierra Amarilla, 1988 (Box 94 (Oversize))
        - Pond, Tierra Amarilla, 1988 (Box 94 (Oversize))
        - Rafael Flores, Tierra Amarilla, 1988 (Box 94 (Oversize))
      - 14 inches by 20 inches, This subseries consists of photographic prints, 14 inches by 20 inches, in mats, 16 inches by 27 inches.
        - Peoples Ditch and Olders Barn in Colorado, Gallegos Ranch, San Luis, Colorado, 1995 (Box 95 (Oversize))
        - Hay Bales, Gallegos Ranch, San Luis, Colorado, 1995 (Box 95 (Oversize))
        - Cutting Hay, Gallegos Ranch, San Luis, Colorado, 1995 (Box 95 (Oversize))
        - Headgate, Rio Culebra Watershed, San Luis, Colorado, 1995 (Box 95 (Oversize))
        - Sociedad Protectora Mutualista de Trabajadores Unidos, Chama, Colorado, 1995 (Box 95 (Oversize))
        - Abandoned House, San Luis, Colorado, 1995 (Box 95 (Oversize))
        - La Presa Sierra Acequia, Chacon, New Mexico, 1999 (Box 95 (Oversize))
        - Vega, Mora River, Mora, New Mexico, 1999 (Box 95 (Oversize))
        - Herding Cattle, Chacon, New Mexico, 1999 (Box 95 (Oversize))
        - Agua Negra, New Mexico, 1992 (Box 95 (Oversize))
        - Milpa, Chimayó, New Mexico, undated (Box 95 (Oversize))
        - Calvario, Agua Negra, New Mexicoo, 1992 (Box 95 (Oversize))
    - Images of San Isidro
      This group of photographs relate to San Isidro, the patron saint of farmers and agriculture, which formed part of an exhibition at the Maxwell Museum at the University of New Mexico in Albuquerque, 2003-2004.
      Organized under two headings by print size: 11 inches by 14 inches and 16 inches by 20 inches.
      - 11 inches by 14 inches, This group of material consists of photographic prints, 11 inches by 14 inches, in mats, 16 inches by 20 inches.
        - Untitled photographic prints, undated; 3 (Box 96 (Oversize))
      - 16 inches by 20 inches, This group of material consists of photographic prints, 16 inches by 20 inches, in mats, 22 inches by 28 inches
        - Untitled photographs, undated; 7 (Box 97 (Oversize))
    - Desde de Nuevo México and Other Prints, This group of material consists of photographic prints, 16 inches by 20 inches, in mats, 20 inches by 28 inches, except where noted.
      This group of material consists of photographic prints document the religious traditions and customs of the mestizo people of the Upper Rio Grande region of Mexico and New Mexico.
      - Couple, Tomé, 1989; 1 photographic print, 16 inches by 20 inches, in a mats, 19 inches by 25 inches. (Box 98 (Oversize))
      - Crawling Pilgrim, Tomé, 1991; 1 photographic print, 16 inches by 20 inches, in a mats, 19 inches by 25 inches. (Box 98 (Oversize))
      - Edwin Berry with Drum, El Cerro, Tomé, 1992 (Box 99 (Oversize))
        Alternate title in Nuevo México Profundo: Edwyn y su Tombé.
      - Hermanos de la Morada,Tomé, 1992 (Box 99 (Oversize))
      - Horacio Martinez, Martineztown, 1992 (Box 88 (Oversize))
      - Scapular, Tomé, 1992; 1 photographic prints, 16 inches by 20 inches, in a mats, 19 inches by 25 inches. (Box 98 (Oversize))
        Alternate title in Nuevo México Profundo: Escapulario.
      - Altar, Tomé, 1993 (Box 99 (Oversize))
      - Pilgrim With Virgin, Tomé, 1993 (Box 99 (Oversize))
        Alternate title in Nuevo México Profundo: Agua de la Vida.
      - Pray For My Sister, Tomé, 1993; 1 photographic print, 16 inches by 20 inches, in a mats, 19 inches by 25 inches. (Box 98 (Oversize))
        Alternate title in Nuevo México Profundo: Recuerdos de Robyn.
      - El Toro Peleando, San Luis, 1993 (Box 99 (Oversize))
      - La Victoria del Rey Alfonso, Santa Cruz, 1993 (Box 100 (Oversize))
      - Los Cautivos, Talpa, 1995 (Box 100 (Oversize))
      - Moctezuma y su Hija, Tortugas, 1996 (Box 100 (Oversize))
      - Música para Guadalupe, Tortugas, 1996 (Box 100 (Oversize))
      - Cuerno Verde y Don Carlos Fernández, Alcalde, 1999 (Box 100 (Oversize))
    - Hermanitos Comanchitos: Indo-Hispano Rituals of Captivity and Redemption
      This group of material consists of digital images used to design and create finished plates for Gandert's work, Hermanitos Comanchitos: Indo-Hispano Rituals of Captivity and Redemption, with Enrique R. Lamadrid (Albuquerque: University of New Mexico Press, 2003).
      - Digital files for book, 2003; 1 video disc
        Stored in: Restricted Fragile Box 102. Reference copies of electronic files may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information. Disk # 20050620-a.0001.
    - America 24/7, 1 DVD
      Stored in: Restricted Fragile Box 102. Reference copies of electronic files may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information. Disk # 20050620-a.0002
      This group of material contains commissioned digital images, including portraits, photo-essays on body modification, depictions of Mexican food preparation and Mexican students from the border city of Paloma, Mexico who are bussed to New Mexico public schools.
      - Commissioned photographic prints, including portraits and photographic essays., 1 video disc
        Stored in: Restricted Fragile Box 102. Reference copies of electronic files may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information. Disk # 20050620-a.0002.
  - Printed Material
    - Posters for Heating Up: Coping with Climate Change in the Southwest event, 1999-2000, undated; 2 (Box 101 (Oversize))
      Poster with an image by Gandert for an event that addressed the effects of global warming and regional climate change on the peoples and places of the Southwest hosted by the Center for the Southwest, University of New Mexico in April 2003.
  - Restricted Fragile Material
    - Computer media (20050620-a.0001 - 20050620-a.0002), 2 video discs (Box 102)
- December 2006 Acquisition, 1986-2005; 5; 1.79; (20 boxes) + 7 broadsides oversize
  Box 129 (video recordings): Restricted Fragile Material. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
  The December 2006 Acquisition consists of black-and-white photographic prints and video recordings that document exhibitions and projects by Gandert, 1988-2005.
  Organized into two subseries: Photographs and Video Recordings.
  - Photographs
    Organized into seven subseries: Tierra O Muerte; Nuevo México Profundo; The Plazas of New Mexico; Bolivia and Mexico, Prints for a Fondation Henri Cartier-Bresson Award; Gifts of the Land: New Mexico's Farm and Ranch Women; LLano Estacado: Island in the Sky; and Miscellaneous Prints.
    - Tierra O Muerte, This group of material consists of photographic prints, 11 inches by 14 inches.
      This group of photographs comes from an exhibition that explores land rights disputes in New Mexico. These images were part of a exhibition related to Emiliano Zapata, a leading figure in the Mexican Revolution and the founder of the agrarian movement called Zapatismo. The exhibit occurred at the Johnson Gallery at the University New Mexico in Albuquerque in 2005.
      - Reies Lopéz Tijerina, 20th Anniversary of Tierra Amarilla Courthouse Raid, Coyote, New Mexico, 1986 (Box 128 (Oversize))
      - Amador Flores, Tierra Amarilla, New Mexico, 1988 (Box 128 (Oversize))
      - Tierra O Muerte, Tierra Amarilla, 1988 (Box 128 (Oversize))
    - Nuevo México Profundo
      This group of photographs comes from an exhibition depicting rituals of Indo-Hispanic people. The exhibit occurred at the National Hispanic Culture Center of New Mexico, Albuquerque, in 2000-2001. Many photographs appeared in Gandert's co-authored book of the same title.
      - Matted Prints
        Organized under two headings by print size: 16 inches by 20 inches and 13.5 inches by 24 inches.
        - 16 inches by 20 inches, This group of material consists of photographic prints, 16 inches by 20 inches, in mats, 22 inches by 28 inches.
          - Despedida, Barrio San José, Albuquerque, 1986 (Box 103 (Oversize))
          - Procesión de San Lorenzo, Bernalillo, 1987 (Box 103 (Oversize))
          - Soldados de San Antonio, San Antonito, 1988 (Box 103 (Oversize))
          - Altar de la Esquina, Barrio San José, Albuquerque, 1989 (Box 103 (Oversize))
          - Pasos al Calvario, Tomé, 1989 (Box 103 (Oversize))
          - Devoción de Mano Lupe, Tomé, 1989 (Box 103 (Oversize))
          - Malinche y su Abuela, Picurís, 1992 (Box 103 (Oversize))
          - El Gobernador, Picurís, 1992 (Box 104 (Oversize))
          - Escapulario, Tomé, 1992 (Box 104 (Oversize))
          - Sueño del Abuelo, Picurís, 1992 (Box 104 (Oversize))
          - Edwin y su Tombé, Tomé, 1992 (Box 104 (Oversize))
          - Abuelo Charro, Juárez, México, 1993 (Box 104 (Oversize))
          - Adorando a San Luis Gonzaga, San Luis, 1993 (Box 104 (Oversize))
          - Recuerdos de Robyn, Tomé, 1993 (Box 104 (Oversize))
          - Devotos del Cerro, "A" Mountain, 1993 (Box 105 (Oversize))
          - Danzantes de la Plaza, Juárez, México, 1993 (Box 105 (Oversize))
          - Ojos al Cielo, Tomé, 1993 (Box 105 (Oversize))
          - Matachines de Noche Buena, Picurís, 1993 (Box 105 (Oversize))
          - Batalla de Moros y Cristianos, Santa Cruz, 1993 (Box 105 (Oversize))
          - Soldado de la Santa Cruz, Santa Cruz, 1993 (Box 105 (Oversize))
          - Guadalupano, Juárez, México, 1993 (Box 105 (Oversize))
          - Dolor de Abuelo, Juárez, México, 1993 (Box 106 (Oversize))
          - Luminaria, Picurís, 1993 (Box 106 (Oversize))
          - Fe y Orgullo, Juárez, México, 1993 (Box 106 (Oversize))
          - Indito de la Sierra, Juárez, México, 1993 (Box 106 (Oversize))
          - Matachines de Carrizo, Tortugas, 1993 (Box 106 (Oversize))
          - Siempre la Cruz, Chimayó, 1993 (Box 106 (Oversize))
          - Galento el Embajador, Alcalde, 1994 (Box 106 (Oversize))
          - Sombra del Monarca, Picurís, 1994 (Box 107 (Oversize))
          - El Abuelo y su Gente, Alcalde, 1994 (Box 107 (Oversize))
          - Malinche y Abuelo, Picurís, 1995 (Box 107 (Oversize))
          - Los Cautivos, Talpa, 1995 (Box 107 (Oversize))
          - Nuestro Señor de Esquipulas, Chimayó, 1995 (Box 107 (Oversize))
          - Músicos y Santos, Picurís, 1995 (Box 107 (Oversize))
          - Peregrinos de la Salud, Chimayó, 1996 (Box 107 (Oversize))
          - Abuela, Picurís, 1996 (Box 108 (Oversize))
          - Las Malinches, Tortugas, 1996 (Box 108 (Oversize))
          - Abuelo Sumiso, Alcalde, 1996 (Box 108 (Oversize))
          - Música para Guadalupe, Tortugas, 1996 (Box 108 (Oversize))
          - Memorias del Cautivo, Talpa, 1996 (Box 108 (Oversize))
          - Sempre Devoto, Chimayó, 1996 (Box 108 (Oversize))
          - Monarca y su Malinche, Alcalde, 1996 (Box 108 (Oversize))
          - Comanchitos de Noche Buena, Bernalillo, 1996 (Box 109 (Oversize))
          - Cumbre de la Cruz, Tomé, 1996 (Box 109 (Oversize))
          - Nevada del Año Nuevo, Talpa, 1996 (Box 109 (Oversize))
          - Malinche Tonantzina, Chimayó, 1996 (Box 109 (Oversize))
          - Misericordia de Chimayó, Chimayó, 1996 (Box 109 (Oversize))
          - Pelea de los Abuelos, Tortugas, 1996 (Box 109 (Oversize))
          - Vuelta de la Malinche, Alcalde, 1996 (Box 109 (Oversize))
          - Capilla de Guadalupe, Tortugas, 1996 (Box 110 (Oversize))
          - Armas de los Tiguas, Tortugas, 1996 (Box 110 (Oversize))
          - Santos y Niños, Chimayó, 1996 (Box 110 (Oversize))
          - Bendición de las Aguas, Atrisco, 1997 (Box 110 (Oversize))
          - Tres Músicos, Alcalde, 1997 (Box 110 (Oversize))
          - Dulces y Tragos, Talpa, 1997 (Box 110 (Oversize))
          - Capilla de Talpa, Talpa, 1997 (Box 110 (Oversize))
          - Juan Dieguito, Alameda, 1997 (Box 111 (Oversize))
          - Eduardo y la Virgen, Alameda, 1997 (Box 111 (Oversize))
          - Tres Generaciones Cantando, Ranchos de Taos, 1997 (Box 111 (Oversize))
          - Ojos al Cielo, San Antonio, 1998 (Box 111 (Oversize))
          - Orgullo del Guadalupano, Ranchos de Anapra, México, 1998 (Box 111 (Oversize))
          - Abuelo y la Muerte, Ranchos de Anapra, México, 1998 (Box 111 (Oversize))
          - Atrocidades de la Perijundia, San Antonio, 1998 (Box 111 (Oversize))
          - Bendiciones del Desierto, Ranchos de Anapra, México, 1998 (Box 112 (Oversize))
          - Danza del Aguila, Talpa, 1998 (Box 112 (Oversize))
          - Javier y su Hijita, Ranchos de Anapra, México, 1998 (Box 112 (Oversize))
          - Niños y la Muerte, Ranchos de Anapra, México, 1998 (Box 112 (Oversize))
          - San Antonio Matachín, San Antonio, 1998 (Box 112 (Oversize))
          - Devoción de los Apaches, Juárez, México, 1998 (Box 112 (Oversize))
          - La Fe de los Hijos, Tomé, 1999 (Box 112 (Oversize))
          - Balazo del Arzobispo, Tortugas, 1999 (Box 113 (Oversize))
          - Adorando a San Lorenzo, Bernalillo, 1999 (Box 113 (Oversize))
          - Peregrino y su Quiote, Tortugas, 1999 (Box 113 (Oversize))
          - Danza del Monarca, Picurís, 1999 (Box 113 (Oversize))
          - Baile del Borracho, Abiquiú, 1999 (Box 113 (Oversize))
          - Plumas en el Viento, Tortugas, 1999 (Box 113 (Oversize))
          - Peregrino de la Salud, Tomé, 1999 (Box 113 (Oversize))
          - Quiotes en la Puerta, Tortugas, 1999 (Box 114 (Oversize))
          - Toritos Capados, Alcalde, 1999 (Box 114 (Oversize))
          - Devociones Guadalupanas, Tortugas, 1999 (Box 114 (Oversize))
          - Cuerno Verde y Don Carlos Fernández, Alcalde, 1999 (Box 114 (Oversize))
          - Abuelo Caído, Alcalde, 1999 (Box 114 (Oversize))
          - Untitled photographs, undated; 7 (Box 115 (Oversize))
        - 13.5 inches by 24 inches, This group of material consists of panoramic photographic prints. 13.5 inches by 24 inches, in mats, 20 inches by 36 inches.
          - Mañanitas del Niño Manuel, Ranchos de Taos, 1995 (Box 116 (Oversize))
          - Al Pie de la Cruz, Chimayó, 1996 (Box 116 (Oversize))
          - El Poder de la Malinche, Alcalde, 1996 (Box 116 (Oversize))
          - Untitled photographs, undated; 2 (Box 116 (Oversize))
      - Unmatted Prints
        Organized under two headings by print size: 20 inches by 24 inches and 30 inches by 40 inches.
        - 20 inches by 24 inches
          - La Malinche y su Luz, San Antonito, 1988 (Box 117 (Oversize))
          - Arco de Triunfo, Bernalillo, 1991 (Box 117 (Oversize))
          - Hermanos de la Morada, Tomé, 1992 (Box 117 (Oversize))
          - Trompetas y Clarines, Tomé, 1992 (Box 117 (Oversize))
          - Vísperas de la Virgen, Juárez, México, 1993 (Box 117 (Oversize))
          - El Toro Peleando, San Luis, 1993 (Box 117 (Oversize))
          - General Azteca Chichimeca, Tortugas, 1993 (Box 117 (Oversize))
          - Cerro de Tomé, Tomé, 1993 (Box 117 (Oversize))
          - La Victoria del Rey Alfonso, Santa Cruz, 1993 (Box 117 (Oversize))
          - Orgullo de Cuerno Verde, Alcalde, 1994 (Box 117 (Oversize))
          - Orgullo del Matachín, Alcalde, 1995 (Box 117 (Oversize))
          - Juan Diego y su Reina, Juárez, México, 1995 (Box 117 (Oversize))
          - El Toro, Picurís, 1996 (Box 117 (Oversize))
          - Guadalupana del Alma, Tortugas, 1996 (Box 117 (Oversize))
          - Tierra Sagrada, Chimayó, 1996 (Box 118 (Oversize))
          - Moctezuma y su Hija, Tortugas, 1996 (Box 118 (Oversize))
          - Alegria de los Matachines, Picurís, 1996 (Box 118 (Oversize))
          - Palabra de Dios, Chimayó, 1996 (Box 118 (Oversize))
          - El Comanche David, Talpa, 1996 (Box 118 (Oversize))
          - Las Comanchas y sus Cautivas, Los Griegos, 1997 (Box 118 (Oversize))
          - Entrega de San Ysidro, Atrisco, 1997 (Box 118 (Oversize))
          - Tormento de los Toritos, Alcalde, 1997 (Box 118 (Oversize))
          - Baile Redondo, Llano Quemado, 1997 (Box 118 (Oversize))
          - Baile del Espantado, Llano Quemado, 1998 (Box 118 (Oversize))
          - Soldado de la Virgen, Ranchos de Anapra, México, 1998 (Box 118 (Oversize))
          - Floyd y su Tombé, Abiquiú, 1999 (Box 118 (Oversize))
          - Untitled photograph, undated (Box 118 (Oversize))
        - 30 inches by 40 inches
          - Antes de la Batalla, Alcalde, 1994 (Box 119 (Broadside oversize))
          - Linda Elena, Talpa, 1995 (Box 120 (Broadside oversize))
          - David Gonzales, Talpa, 1995 (Box 121 (Broadside oversize))
          - Danza de la Tejida, Tortugas, 1996 (Box 122 (Broadside oversize))
          - Baile del Paseado, Talpa, 1997 (Box 123 (Broadside oversize))
          - Procesión, Ranchos de Anapra, México, 1998 (Box 124 (Broadside oversize))
          - Untitled photographs, undated; 2 (Box 125 (Broadside oversize))
    - The Plazas of New Mexico
      This group of photographs documents public squares and spaces in New Mexico. They appeared in Gandert's co-authored book, The Plazas of New Mexico, as well as in an exhibition at Pearl Hall, School of Architecture, University of New Mexico, Albuquerque, October 2011.
      - 11 inches by 14 inches
        - Wedding photographs on the Plaza, Las Vegas, New Mexico, 2001 (Box 126 (Oversize))
        - Heritage Days Queen and Princesses in Portales near the Courthouse Square, 2004 (Box 126 (Oversize))
        - Crowd Viewing Temporary Bandstand, Heritage Days, City Park, Portales, New Mexico, 2004 (Box 126 (Oversize))
        - Cooking Chicharrones for Fiesta, Monticello, New Mexico, 2004; 3 (Box 126 (Oversize))
        - Community Fiesta Meal, Monticello, New Mexico, 2005 (Box 126 (Oversize))
        - The Patron Saint of Monticello San Ignacio, Fiesta Procession, Monticello, New Mexico, 2005; 4 (Box 126 (Oversize))
        - Fiesta Band, Monticello, New Mexico, 2005 (Box 126 (Oversize))
        - Fiesta Dancers, Monticello, New Mexico, 2005 (Box 126 (Oversize))
        - Plaza Rats, Santa Fe, New Mexico, 2005; 2 (Box 126 (Oversize))
      - 16 inches by 20 inches
        - Plaza Rats, Santa Fe, New Mexico, 2005 (Box 127 (Oversize))
    - Bolivia and Mexico, Prints for a Fondation Henri Cartier-Bresson Award, This group of material consists of photographic prints, 11 inches by 14 inches.
      This group of photographs gathered by Gandert relates to an entry for an award from the Fondation Henri Cartier-Bresson. The images document celebrations in Bolivia, including Carnaval de Oruro and La Fiesta del Señor Jesús del Gran Poder in La Paz, as well as a wheat harvest. The group also includes images from an Easter Celebration in Juárez, Mexico.
      Organized under three headings: Carnaval de Oruro, La Fiesta del Señor Jesús del Gran Poder, and Other Prints.
      - Carnaval de Oruro
        - China y Morenas, Oruro, Bolivia, undated (Box 128 (Oversize))
        - Chinita y Cholita, Oruro, Bolivia, undated (Box 128 (Oversize))
        - Niños Negritos, Oruro, Bolivia, undated (Box 128 (Oversize))
        - Los Tobos Salta, Oruro, Bolivia, undated (Box 128 (Oversize))
      - La Fiesta del Señor Jesús del Gran Poder
        - Banda de Música Nueva América, La Paz, Bolivia, undated (Box 128 (Oversize))
        - China Morena, La Paz, Bolivia, undated (Box 128 (Oversize))
        - Chinas Morenas Antes de La Entrada, La Paz, Bolivia, undated (Box 128 (Oversize))
        - Esclavo Torturado, Alegoria, La Paz, Bolivia, undated (Box 128 (Oversize))
        - Moreno, La Paz, Bolivia, undated (Box 128 (Oversize))
        - Los Tobos, La Paz, Bolivia (Box 128 (Oversize))
      - Other Prints
        - Easter Celebration, Raramuri Barrio, Juárez, México, 2004; 2 (Box 128 (Oversize))